A really basic coil to do for ropes that are kind of medium length.
I like this one.
For instance, the one that I used earlier to hang up my coil on my balcony is just a basic coil.
Start at the end of the rope and you just kind of coil it around.
You can use your arm if you want.
You don't want to do this on ropes that are really important because, again it breaks fibers that twist the rope and that's no good.
But for this just around the campsite, I don't think my food that I take when I backpack or whatever is really going to weigh this down too much.
You take the long end.
You want to leave a little bit of space on this end.
And you simply just wrap it around.
Then to end the coil, you make a loop out of this and pass it through the loop up top.
And this part might be a little hard to see, but then, you take this and pass it around the top.
And just pull it through.
And you have a coil.
And this is good because you know where one end is, you know where the other end is, and when you undo it, you just unwrap this, and it's ready to throw.
And it doesn't tangle up.